Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Katrin and today we've got a lesson for you that's about an unusual topic, something
我是Katrin，今天我们要给大家上一节关于一个不寻常话题的课，这个话题
we've never talked about here on EnglishPod.
我们以前在EnglishPod上从未讨论过。
That's right.
没错。
As you know in EnglishPod, we like to talk about all sorts of topics, especially topics
正如你们所知，在EnglishPod，我们喜欢谈论各种话题，尤其是那些
that are real life topics.
贴近现实生活的话题。
So probably a lot of things that you won't find in your normal English notebooks or English
所以很可能有很多东西是你们在普通英语笔记本或英语
learning books.
学习书里找不到的。
That's right.
没错。
So we want to tell you in advance, today's lesson is about drugs.
所以我们想提前告诉你们，今天的课是关于毒品的。
So if you're a younger user or you have, if you have kids, maybe they shouldn't listen
所以如果你是年轻用户，或者你有孩子，也许他们不应该听
to today's lesson.
今天的课。
But you're going to learn a lot of the names for drugs and also how to turn down an offer
但你们会学到很多毒品的名称，以及如何拒绝
of drugs.
毒品的诱惑。
So let's check out today's dialogue and we'll be back in a moment to talk about the things
那么让我们来看看今天的对话，我们一会儿回来讨论你们听到的内容。
that you've heard.
Hey man, you want to buy some weed?
嘿，哥们儿，想买点weed吗？
Some what?
什么？
Some weed, you know, pot, ganja, Mary Jane, some chronic.
就是weed，你知道的，pot、ganja、Mary Jane、chronic。
Oh, uh, no thanks.
哦，呃，不用了，谢谢。
I also have blow if you prefer to do a few lines.
我也有blow，如果你想来几行的话。
No, I'm okay, really.
不用了，我真的没事。
Come on man, I even got dope and acid.
别这样，哥们儿，我甚至还有dope和acid。
Try some.
试试吧。
Do you really have all of these drugs?
你真的有所有这些毒品吗？
Where do you get them from?
你从哪儿弄来的？
I got my connections.
我有我的门路。
Just tell me what you want and I'll even give you an ounce for free.
告诉我你想要什么，我甚至可以免费给你一盎司。
Hmm, sounds good.
嗯，听起来不错。
Let's see.
让我想想。
I want, yeah, I want you to put your hands behind your head.
我想要，嗯，我要你把手放在脑后。
You are under arrest.
你被捕了。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So as Catherine mentioned, obviously everywhere in the world, maybe most likely you've been
正如Catherine提到的，显然在世界各地，很可能你曾经
offered drugs.
被人兜售过毒品。
So we're not only going to talk about drugs, but we're also going to give you some vocab
所以我们不仅要讨论毒品，还会给你们一些英语词汇，
in English, how to reject or turn down the offer of drugs.
教你们如何拒绝或推掉毒品的诱惑。
And now what we're going to take a look at, let's start in language takeaway with some
现在我们要看看，让我们从语言要点开始，学习一些
of the names of these drugs in English.
这些毒品的英文名称。
Language takeaway.
语言要点。
Okay, so we're in language takeaway here and I want to warn you, some of these words are
好的，我们现在在语言要点部分，我想提醒你们，其中一些词是
slang.
俚语。
That means they're not words from like a dictionary.
这意味着它们不是字典里的词。
These are words people use when they're talking to each other in daily life or words that
这些是人们在日常生活中交谈时使用的词，或者是你
you hear on the street.
在街上听到的词。
That's right.
没错。
You may even hear them a lot in movies as well.
你甚至可能在电影里经常听到它们。
Yes, movies and TV.
是的，电影和电视里。
So this first one, weed, is something, there's even a TV show called Weeds.
所以第一个词，weed，甚至有一部电视剧叫《Weeds》。
That's right, that talks about this topic.
没错，就是讲这个话题的。
So weed is the street name or the most common name for the drug marijuana.
所以weed是大麻这种毒品的街头名称或最常用名称。
That's right.
没错。
Marijuana is the drug name, but there are many, many, many other names in English that
大麻是毒品的学名，但在英语中还有很多很多其他的名称
you will hear.
你会听到。
So weed is one of them.
所以weed是其中之一。
A weed is a kind of thing that grows like grass or a flower that you cut because you
weed是一种像草或花一样生长的东西，你会把它割掉，因为
don't want it.
你不想要它。
It's bad.
它不好。
It smells bad.
它闻起来难闻。
That's exactly right.
完全正确。
So the colloquial name for marijuana is weed and obviously the person that's being offered
所以大麻的口语名称是weed，显然被兜售这些毒品的人
these drugs doesn't understand what that means.
不明白那是什么意思。
So he goes on and he gives a couple of different other street names for the same drug.
所以他继续说了几种同一种毒品的其他街头名称。
So the first one, so the next one is pot.
所以第一个，下一个是pot。
That's right.
没错。
So he says pot or ganja or Mary Jane or even chronic.
所以他说pot或ganja或Mary Jane，甚至chronic。
So all of these are synonyms.
所以所有这些词都是同义词。
They mean exactly the same thing.
它们的意思完全一样。
They all mean marijuana.
它们都指大麻。
But then after that, the drug dealer offers other kinds of drugs.
但之后，毒贩子又提供了其他种类的毒品。
He says blow.
他说blow。
So now we may know the verb to blow, right?
现在我们可能知道动词to blow，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
To blow air.
吹气。
But in this case, it's a noun.
但在这里，它是一个名词。
Okay.
好的。
So he says, I have blow.
所以他说，我有blow。
That's right.
没错。
So he's offering this drug called blow.
所以他正在兜售这种叫blow的毒品。
And what is blow?
那“blow”是什么意思？
Blow is the street name for cocaine.
“Blow”是可卡因的街头黑话。
So there's a very famous movie called Blow and it was about selling cocaine.
有一部很有名的电影就叫《Blow》，讲的就是贩卖可卡因的故事。
So after he talks about having blow, he also says if you want to do a few lines.
所以他说完“blow”之后，又提到“如果你想吸几行”。
And so this is what you'll commonly hear people saying how they do this drug.
这就是你常听到人们谈论吸食这种毒品的方式。
That's right.
没错。
So for example, you may know that many drugs, they're consumed in different ways.
比如说，你可能知道很多毒品有不同的吸食方式。
For example, weed, people smoke it, right?
比如大麻，人们是抽的，对吧？
In this case, when we're talking about cocaine or blow, then that's why he refers to do a
在这个例子里，当我们谈论可卡因或“blow”时，他才会提到“吸几行”。
few lines.
几行。
All right.
好的。
Because people breathe it in through their nose.
因为人们是通过鼻子吸进去的。
That's right.
没错。
So it's a colloquial way of saying of how you say that, how you consume this drug.
所以这是一种口语化的说法，表示你如何吸食这种毒品。
Okay.
好的。
So moving along, there's two more drugs that got mentioned in today's dialogue.
继续往下，今天的对话中还提到了另外两种毒品。
They're dope and acid.
它们是“dope”和“acid”。
Now dope can mean two different things.
“Dope”可以指两种不同的东西。
Sometimes it means marijuana, like some of those other words we heard earlier, but sometimes
有时它指大麻，就像我们之前听到的那些词一样，但有时
it also means a very, very serious drug called crack cocaine.
它也指一种非常非常严重的毒品，叫快克可卡因。
Okay.
好的。
And that's something that people breathe in and it's very, very addictive.
那是一种人们吸食的东西，而且非常非常容易上瘾。
Yeah, that's right.
是的，没错。
And also the other word that we have there, or the other drug acid, you may know the word
还有我们提到的另一个词，或者说另一种毒品“acid”，你可能知道“acid”
acid is a very harmful substance.
这个词指的是一种非常有害的物质。
Like for example, batteries, they have a certain type of acid that for example, will melt metal
比如电池里含有某种酸，这种酸能融化金属，
or if it gets on your skin, it will burn you.
或者沾到皮肤上会烧伤你。
That's right.
没错。
But acid when it's a drug means LSD.
但“acid”作为毒品时，指的是LSD。
And that is a drug that people take that makes them see things.
那是一种人们服用后会产生幻觉的毒品。
So it's called a hallucinogenic.
所以它被称为致幻剂。
It makes you see crazy things.
它会让你看到疯狂的东西。
And it was very, very popular in the 1970s.
它在20世纪70年代非常非常流行。
That's right.
没错。
So that's acid or LSD.
所以那就是“acid”或LSD。
Very good.
非常好。
So we've taken a look at a lot of vocab here, specifically all the drugs.
我们这里看了很多词汇，特别是所有毒品的名称。
Why don't we go back to our dialogue?
我们为什么不回到对话中呢？
Let's take another listen and we'll be back to talk a little bit more.
让我们再听一遍，然后回来再聊一会儿。
Hey man, you want to buy some weed?
嘿，哥们，想买点大麻吗？
Some what?
什么？
Weed, you know, pot, ganja, Mary Jane, some chronic.
大麻，你知道的，weed、pot、ganja、Mary Jane、chronic。
Oh, no.
哦，不了。
No, thanks.
不了，谢谢。
I also have blow if you prefer to do a few lines.
我也有可卡因，如果你想吸几行的话。
No, I'm okay.
不，我没事。
Really?
真的吗？
Come on, man.
别这样，哥们。
I even got dope and acid.
我甚至还有“dope”和“acid”。
Try some.
试试吧。
Do you really have all of these drugs?
你真的有所有这些毒品吗？
Where do you get them from?
你从哪儿弄来的？
I got my connections.
我有我的门路。
Just tell me what you want and I'll even give you an ounce for free.
告诉我你想要什么，我甚至可以免费给你一盎司。
Sounds good.
听起来不错。
Let's see.
让我想想。
I want.
我想要。
Yeah.
嗯。
I want you to put your hands behind your head.
我要你把手放在脑后。
You are under arrest.
你被捕了。
Oh.
哦。
Okay.
好的。
So now in fluency builder, we've got a couple of phrases for you about the other side of
那么在流利度构建环节，我们为你准备了一些短语，关于事情的另一面，
things, how to say no to drugs and what you might hear from a police officer like, like
如何拒绝毒品，以及你可能从警察那里听到的话，就像
we hear in today's dialogue.
我们在今天的对话中听到的那样。
That's right.
没错。
So let's take a look at these phrases in fluency builder.
那我们来看看流利度构建中的这些短语。
Fluency builder.
流利度构建。
So the first one we hear is no thanks.
第一个我们听到的是“不了，谢谢”。
So the guy says, um, no thanks.
所以那个人说，嗯，不了，谢谢。
He doesn't want the drugs.
他不想要毒品。
That's right.
没错。
So obviously you're being offered something that you don't like.
所以很明显，别人给你提供了你不喜欢的东西。
Let's take into consideration drugs or maybe somebody wants to offer you a drink or somebody
我们考虑一下毒品，或者可能有人想给你一杯酒，或者有人
wants to take you on a date.
想约你出去。
You can say, no thanks.
你可以说“不了，谢谢”。
No thanks.
不了，谢谢。
So, hey Marco, you want a drink?
那么，嘿，Marco，你想喝一杯吗？
I'm going to go right now.
我现在就去。
It's only like two o'clock, but you know, we could go for a drink.
现在才两点钟，但你知道，我们可以去喝一杯。
No thanks.
不了，谢谢。
No.
不。
Oh, okay.
哦，好吧。
Right.
对。
And now we also have another phrase.
现在我们还有另一个短语。
So if a person insists, the person is continually insisting like, Oh, come on, come on, come
所以如果一个人坚持，他不停地坚持说，比如，哦，来吧，来吧，来
on, Marco.
吧，马可。
Let's go for a drink.
我们去喝一杯吧。
I really want a drink.
我真的很想喝一杯。
Come with me.
跟我一起去吧。
Right.
对。
And I, and you can say, no, I'm okay.
然后你，你可以说，不，我没事。
Really.
真的。
So it may sound confusing.
这听起来可能有点让人困惑。
I am okay.
我没事。
Because that would mean you're in good health.
因为那可能意味着你身体很好。
I feel good.
我感觉不错。
But I am in this case, when you say to someone, no, I'm okay.
但在这里，当你对某人说，不，我没事。
You're saying, no, I'm fine the way I am.
你是在说，不，我现在这样挺好的。
I don't, I don't really need to do anything.
我其实，其实不需要做什么。
I don't need it.
我不需要它。
So I'm okay means I don't need it.
所以“我没事”意思就是我不需要它。
All right, and this is a great way to, to, to really say, listen, no, I don't want it.
好的，这是一种很好的方式，来，来，来明确地说，听着，不，我不想要。
Okay.
好的。
So those are the two ways that we have in, in which you can say no, we're going to give
所以这就是我们有的两种方式，你可以用它们来说“不”，我们会在
you a couple of more towards the end of the lesson, but let's take a look very quickly
课程快结束时再给你几个，但让我们快速看一下
at our next phrase.
下一个短语。
When the police officer said you are under arrest.
当警察说“你被捕了”的时候。
All right.
好的。
So the man didn't know, the person didn't know this was a police officer.
所以那个人不知道，这个人不知道这是个警察。
And finally in the end he says, you are under arrest.
最后他说道：“你被捕了。”
That's right.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
So in the movies, when they put the, uh, handcuffs on somebody, um, the, the preposition is under,
所以在电影里，当他们给某人戴上手铐时，嗯，介词用的是“under”，
it's strange, but you just have to remember this as a phrase.
这有点奇怪，但你只需要把它当作一个短语来记。
You're under arrest.
你被捕了。
I am arresting you.
我要逮捕你。
That means you are going to the police station with me.
这意味着你要跟我去警察局。
You broke the law.
你犯法了。
Right.
没错。
Or you can say, oh, uh, Tim is under arrest.
或者你可以说，哦，呃，蒂姆被捕了。
He's at the police station right now.
他现在在警察局。
Okay.
好的。
All right.
行。
So we've taken a look at a couple of phrases and a couple of different things.
所以我们看了一些短语和一些不同的内容。
Why don't we take another short break?
我们不如再休息一小会儿？
Let's listen to our dialogue and we'll be back in a bit.
让我们听一下对话，一会儿再回来。
Hey man, you want to buy some weed?
嘿，哥们，你想买点大麻吗？
Some what?
什么？
Weed.
大麻。
You know, pot, ganja, Mary Jane, some chronic.
你知道的，大麻、印度大麻、玛丽珍、一些强效大麻。
Oh, uh, no thanks.
哦，呃，不用了，谢谢。
I also have blow if you prefer to do a few lines.
我也有可卡因，如果你想来几行的话。
No, I'm okay.
不，我没事。
Really.
真的。
Come on, man.
别这样，哥们。
I even got dope and acid.
我甚至还有海洛因和迷幻药。
Try some.
试试吧。
Do you really have all of these drugs?
你真的有所有这些毒品吗？
Where do you get them from?
你从哪儿弄来的？
I got my connections.
我有我的门路。
Just tell me what you want and I'll even give you an ounce for free.
告诉我你想要什么，我甚至可以免费给你一盎司。
Hmm.
嗯。
Sounds good.
听起来不错。
Let's see.
让我想想。
I want.
我要。
Yeah.
好。
I want you to put your hands behind your head.
我要你把双手放在脑后。
You are under arrest.
你被捕了。
Dope.
毒品。
All right, so obviously a very serious topic, but at the same time, I think very necessary
好吧，这显然是个非常严肃的话题，但同时，我觉得也很有必要，
because it may happen or you may hear it in a movie and it's part of the English language.
因为这种事可能发生，或者你会在电影里听到，而且它是英语的一部分。
Now obviously we are not advocating or saying that drugs are good or anything.
现在我们显然不是在提倡或说毒品好什么的。
We are saying we are giving you the tools so you know how to recognize when somebody
我们是在给你提供工具，让你知道如何识别当有人
is offering you a drug and the way that you can say no.
向你提供毒品时，以及你可以如何拒绝。
That's right.
没错。
So remember that these are things that you might hear when you're in a country like America
所以记住，这些是你可能在美国这样的国家
or England or Australia.
或英国或澳大利亚听到的东西。
We hope that you don't have to worry about this, but if you do hear it or you hear it
我们希望你不必为此担心，但如果你真的听到或看到它
in a movie, you will understand it.
在电影里，你会明白它的意思。
But Marco, we had some other ways to say no to drugs, right?
但是 Marco，我们还有其他拒绝毒品的方式，对吧？
To say no to something, to refuse.
拒绝某事物，就是说不。
So we heard no thanks and I'm okay.
所以我们听到了“不用了，谢谢”和“我没事”。
But what are some other ways to say no?
但还有哪些其他方式可以说“不”呢？
Well, for example, if the person also persists or insists, you can say, no, I'm good.
嗯，比如，如果对方还坚持或纠缠，你可以说“不，我很好”。
Thank you.
谢谢。
I'm good.
我很好。
Yeah.
是的。
So it doesn't really make sense because you're saying I'm good.
这听起来有点奇怪，因为你说“我很好”。
What does that exactly mean?
这到底是什么意思呢？
So like Marco, you want a cigarette?
就像 Marco，你想来根烟吗？
No, I'm good.
不，我很好。
Thanks.
谢谢。
Okay.
好的。
So that's a way of saying no thanks.
所以这是一种说“不用了，谢谢”的方式。
No thanks.
不用了，谢谢。
I'm okay.
我没事。
Also, I'm cool.
还有，“我没事”。
Not saying like, I'm really cool.
不是说“我真的很酷”。
It's like saying, no, I'm good.
而是像在说“不，我很好”。
I'm cool.
我没事。
Thanks.
谢谢。
That's right.
没错。
I'm cool.
我没事。
I'm thank you.
我谢谢你。
No thank you.
不，谢谢。
Or as well, you can also just say no thank you.
或者，你也可以直接说“不，谢谢”。
I think the most clear is no, I don't smoke or no, I don't do drugs.
我觉得最清楚的是“不，我不抽烟”或“不，我不吸毒”。
Yes, exactly.
是的，没错。
That's the verb that we use when referring to drugs.
这是我们在谈论毒品时用的动词。
You do drugs.
你吸毒。
You don't do drugs.
你不吸毒。
So he does drugs or don't do drugs.
所以他吸毒或不吸毒。
You often hear this phrase.
你经常听到这个短语。
So you can say, listen, no, no thank you.
所以你可以说，“听着，不，不用了，谢谢。”
I'm cool.
我没事。
I don't do drugs.
我不吸毒。
That's right.
没错。
So as we said, this is all the kind of street slang or colloquial, very common ways of
所以就像我们说的，这些都是街头俚语或口语化的表达，在英语中谈论毒品时非常常见。
referring to drugs in English.
谈论毒品时很常用。
So you can keep an eye out for that.
所以你可以留意一下。
If you hear that in movies, now you know more or less what they're referring to.
如果你在电影里听到这些，现在你大概知道他们在说什么了。
And also, of course, if you have any questions, any comments or any suggestions, we are always
当然，如果你有任何问题、任何评论或任何建议，我们随时都在我们的网站 EnglishPod.com 上。
available on our website, EnglishPod.com.
我们期待在那里见到你们，下次再见。
We hope to see you guys there and until next time.
Bye.
再见。